Welcome! In the last lecture, we successfully added this vaulting for our character. And
欢迎!在上一节课中，我们成功地为我们的角色添加了这个跳跃。和
now, when we are near a vaultable surface, we are pressing the same Climb Action key.
现在，当我们在一个可跳跃的表面附近时，我们正在按下相同的攀爬操作键。
We can move our character to a target point that we specify. And this looks cool.
我们可以将角色移动到我们指定的目标点。这看起来很酷。
And before we move on, I'd like to do a little bit of cleanup in my code. So I'm going to
在我们继续之前，我想对我的代码进行一点清理。所以我要去
close my project. Then inside of this custom movement component, I'm going to scroll down
关闭我的项目。然后在此自定义移动组件中，我将向下滚动
to this can start vaulting. I'm going to delete these two truths. So I don't need to see those
这样就可以开始跳马了。我要删除这两个事实。所以我不需要看到那些
debug lines anymore. And next, I'm going to go to my character class, the H. So later,
不再调试代码行。接下来，我要去上我的角色课，H。所以稍后，
we'll need to fill in more code to this header file. And currently, I think this one is a
我们需要在这个头文件中填充更多代码。而目前，我认为这是一个
bit messy with all these forward declares. So I'm going to move them to the top of my
所有这些Forward声明都有点混乱。所以我要把它们移到我的
header file. So select this one, and I'm going to paste it in here and delete the class in
头文件。所以选择这个，我将把它粘贴到这里，并删除中的类
front of it and do the same thing to this camera component. And also, I'm going to create
在它前面，对这个相机组件做同样的事情。此外，我还将创建
code regions. So I'm going to separate these components with this input actions and these
代码区域。所以我将用这个输入操作和这些组件来分隔这些组件
callback functions. So I'm going to scroll to here, then add in panel region. I'm going
回调函数。所以我要滚动到这里，然后添加面板区域。我要走了
to call this region components and delete this class in here. Select all of these four, cut
调用此区域组件并删除此处的此类。将这四个选项全部选中，Cut
them, paste them in here. If your engine version is higher than 5.1, probably you don't have
他们，把他们贴在这里。如果您的引擎版本高于5.1，则可能没有
to do this. The template code in there should be much cleaner than this one. Somehow this
来做这件事。其中的模板代码应该比这个干净得多。不知何故，这就是
version here passed the Apex code review. Next, I'm going to copy this forward declare
这里的版本通过了Apex代码审查。接下来，我要将此声明向前复制
for input math in context and paste it in here. Then delete this class in front of it and
用于在上下文中输入数学并将其粘贴到此处。然后删除它前面的这个类并
copy this one for you input action, paste it in here and delete all of these classes
为您的输入操作复制此类，将其粘贴到此处并删除所有这些类
in here. Just to make this header file a bit cleaner and you'll be much easier for us to
在这里。只是为了让这个头文件更干净一点，我们会更容易
add in more stuff later and delete these two classes. Delete this one and go to the bottom
稍后添加更多内容并删除这两个类。删除这一条，然后转到底部
of it, delete these two classes. And then I'm first going to hide this region. I'm going
其中，删除这两个类。然后我首先要隐藏这个区域。我要走了
to create a new one. So for this region, I'm going to call it input. So all the input related,
去创造一个新的。因此，对于这个区域，我将其称为输入。所以所有的输入都是相关的，
I'm going to put it in here. So cut these three, paste them in here and cut this one,
我要把它放在这里。把这三个剪下来，贴在这里，再剪下这一个，
paste it in here. And along with our climb action, paste it in here. Then I'm going to
把它贴在这里。随着我们的攀登动作，粘贴到这里。然后我要去
hide this region and the last region that I'm going to create. So I'm going to call
隐藏这个区域和我要创建的最后一个区域。所以我要打电话给
this one input callback and I'm going to cut these functions, paste them in here. And
这一个输入回调，我将剪切这些函数，粘贴到这里。和
that's pretty much it. I'm going to try to compile. All right, I have a successful compile
差不多就是这样。我要试着汇编一下。好的，我有一个成功的汇编
and this is how my header file is looking like. So if you'd like to catch up with me,
这就是我的头文件的样子。所以如果你想跟上我的话，
you can pause the video now and give this a go. Welcome back. And the next thing that
你现在可以暂停视频，然后试一试。欢迎回来。接下来的事情是
I like to add into our clamping system is hopping. With the ability to hop, this can
我喜欢加进我们的夹紧系统是跳动的。有了跳跃的能力，它可以
make our clamping system so much better. And these are the things that I want to achieve.
让我们的夹紧系统变得更好。这些都是我想要实现的目标。
So first, I want this action to be a two key action. So in order to trigger hopping during
所以首先，我希望这个行动是两个关键的行动。所以为了在跳跃过程中触发
climbing, our player needs to press both the key for moving the character and the key to
攀登，我们的玩家需要同时按移动角色的键和键来移动角色
trigger the hopping. And I'm only going to allow our character to hop up and down. And
触发跳跃。我只会让我们的角色跳上跳下。和
for the key to trigger hopping, I like it to be the same key as our jump action. So
对于触发跳跃的键，我希望它与我们的跳跃动作是相同的键。所以
when we're moving on the ground, we can press the space bar to jump. And during climbing,
当我们在地面上移动时，我们可以按空格键跳跃。在攀登过程中，
I like to use the same key to trigger hopping. And that's something the new enhanced input
我喜欢使用相同的键来触发跳跃。这是新的增强型输入
system can help us. A vivid example of this would be something like this. If you recall,
系统可以帮助我们。这方面的一个生动例子是这样的。如果你还记得的话，
this is our move function. And this function here is binding to our move action. And instead
这是我们的移动功能。这里的这个函数绑定到我们的移动操作。相反，
of this function, we are checking whether or not our character is climbing. If it is,
在这个函数中，我们正在检查我们的角色是否在攀登。如果是的话，
we handle this climb movement input in here. If it's not, we will handle the ground movement
我们在这里处理爬升动作的输入。如果不是，我们会处理地面移动
input. This solution here works, but this shouldn't really be the way for how we are
输入。这个解决方案在这里是有效的，但这不应该真的是我们现在的方式
using the enhanced input system. So we shouldn't be checking the logic inside of the input
使用增强型输入系统。所以我们不应该检查输入内部的逻辑
level. And instead, we can leave that to our enhanced input system entirely. So what I
水平。取而代之的是，我们可以完全把它留给我们的增强型输入系统。所以我
want here is when the character is on the ground, by pressing the WSAD key, we can only
这里想要的是当角色在地上的时候，通过按WSAD键，我们只能
move the character on the ground. And when the character is climbing, those same keys
移动地面上的角色。当角色在攀登时，同样的键
can only move the character on the surface. We're going to look at how we can do this
只能在表面上移动角色。我们将看看如何做到这一点
later. And in order to achieve what we want, this is the process that we'll follow later.
后来。为了实现我们想要的，这是我们稍后要遵循的过程。
So first, our custom moving component needs to take care of this notifying climb state.
因此，首先，我们的自定义移动组件需要处理这种通知爬升状态。
So when our character is inside of the climb state, I want this moving component to notify
所以当我们的角色处于爬升状态时，我想让这个移动组件通知
our character class. And our character class can respond to it by adding this input mapping
我们的角色班级。我们的字符类可以通过添加此输入映射来响应它
context. So the key bindings inside of this mapping context will only be valid when we
背景。因此，此映射上下文中的键绑定仅在以下情况下有效
are climbing. And once our character exits the climb state, we'll need to remove this
都在攀登。一旦我们的角色退出攀爬状态，我们需要移除这个
input mapping context. And we'll be back to the default mapping context. So we can jump,
输入映射上下文。然后我们将返回到默认的映射上下文。这样我们就可以跳下去了
we can run on the ground. So this hopping action here should only be triggered when
我们可以在地上跑步。因此，此处的跳跃操作应仅在以下情况下触发
we're climbing. And I like to trigger that through player input. So our player will request
我们在往上爬。我喜欢通过玩家的输入来触发它。所以我们的玩家会要求
the hopping and our custom moving component will take it from there and handle the hopping
跳跃和我们的定制移动组件将从那里获取它并处理跳跃
for us. So this is the roadmap that we'll follow. And in this lecture, we're going to
对我们来说。这就是我们要遵循的路线图。在这堂课中，我们将介绍
look at how we can take care of the first step notifying climb state. Go back to my
看看我们如何处理通知爬升状态的第一步。回到我的
code. I'm going to go to the header file of this custom moving component, scroll to the
密码。我将转到此自定义移动组件的头文件，滚动到
top. So for that, I'm going to use a simple delegate to do it. On the top of this header
托普。因此，我将使用一个简单的委托来完成它。在此页眉的顶部
file, I'm going to type in declare underscore delegate. So this is the most basic way to
文件中，我将键入声明下划线委托。所以这是最基本的方法
declare a delegate. Since what we want here is simple, we don't need to create a dynamic
宣布一个代表。因为我们在这里想要的很简单，所以我们不需要创建动态的
multicast delegate or anything like that. A simple delegate with no return value and
多播代理或类似的东西。不带返回值的简单委托和
input parameter specified will do the job. So I'm going to call this delegate F, on,
指定的输入参数将完成此工作。所以我把这个代表称为F，On，
enter climb state. And I'm going to create another delegate. So this one, I have a typo
进入爬升状态。我将创建另一个代表。所以这一个，我有一个打字错误
here. I'm going to copy this name and paste it in here. So this one I'm going to call
这里。我要复制这个名字，然后把它粘贴到这里。所以这一次我要叫它
you F, on, exit, climb state. And then scroll down. Inside of this class, I'm going to create
你，开启，退出，爬升状态。然后向下滚动。在这个类的内部，我将创建
a public section and I'm going to copy the type. So it'll be this F, on, enter climb
一个公共部分，我要复印一下。所以它将是这个F，在，进入攀登
state. I'm going to call this delegate on, enter climb state delegate. And I'm going
州政府。我要请这位代表发言，进入攀登州代表。我要走了
to copy this type. So this F, on, exit, climb state. And I'm going to call it on, exit,
复制此类型。所以这个F，ON，EXIT，爬升状态。我要开始了，退场，
climb state delegate. And then I'm going to execute this delegate if there's a function
攀登州代表。然后，如果有一个函数，我将执行这个委托
bound to it. So I'm going to go to this CPP file and scroll up to on movement mode changed.
捆绑在它身上。因此，我将转到此CPP文件并向上滚动到移动模式已更改。
So in here, so inside of this function, we'll know exactly when the character has entered
所以在这里，所以在这个函数内部，我们将确切地知道字符何时进入
the climb state. So if this is climbing is true, that means we're indeed inside of the
攀爬状态。所以如果这是真的攀登，那就意味着我们确实在
climbing state. I'm going to use the delegate to execute the function. And the function that
攀登状态。我将使用委托来执行该函数。和它的功能
we can use is called execute if bound. So if there's indeed a callback function bound
我们可以使用的是，如果绑定，则称为执行。因此，如果确实有回调函数绑定
to this delegate, it will be executed in there. This is for when the player enters the climb
对于这个委托，它将在那里执行。这是当玩家进入攀登时使用的
state. And I'm going to copy this on, exit, climb state delegate. And this is something
州政府。我要把这个复制下来，退出，爬上州代表。这是一件
that we can take care of in here. So I'm going to call the function execute if bound. So
我们可以在这里处理。所以我将调用函数Execute If Bound。所以
inside of this if check, we are checking if the player has just exited the climb state.
在这个IF检查中，我们正在检查玩家是否刚刚退出爬升状态。
All right. I'm going to try to compile first to see if there are any errors. I have a successful
好的。我将首先尝试编译，看看是否有任何错误。我有一个成功的
compile. And next thing I'm going to create the callback functions inside of our character
编译。接下来，我将在角色内部创建回调函数
class. So go back to the header file. Since I like to handle the input related stuff inside
班级。因此，回到头文件。因为我喜欢在里面处理与输入相关的东西
of those two callback functions, I'm going to place those functions in here. So the first
在这两个回调函数中，我将把它们放在这里。所以第一个
function I'm going to call it void on player enter climb state. Since the delegate we created
函数，当玩家进入攀登状态时，我将其称为无效。由于我们创建的委托
is the most basic one, our callback function doesn't need to have the U function macro.
是最基本的一个，我们的回调函数不需要有U函数宏。
And I'm going to create another function. I'm going to call this on player exit climb state.
我将创建另一个函数。我将把这称为玩家出口爬升状态。
All right. I'm going to create two function bodies. So copy this function and I'm going
好的。我将创建两个功能体。所以复制这个函数，我就去
to place it at the bottom of this CPP file and create another function in here. Paste
将其放在此cpp文件的底部，并在此处创建另一个函数。浆糊
it in here. And first thing we need to bind these two functions. So I'm going to do that
就在这里。首先，我们需要将这两个函数绑定。所以我要这么做
inside of the begin play. I'm first going to check if our custom movement component
在Begin Play的内部。我首先要检查一下我们的自定义移动组件
is valid. If it is, I'm going to access the delegate. So it's called on enter clamp state
是有效的。如果是，我将访问该代表。所以它在进入钳位状态时被称为
delegate and to bind the function, I'm going to use the function by U object. And then
委托和绑定函数，我将通过U对象使用该函数。然后
we'll need to pass in in user object. So which U object has this function, it'll be this
我们需要传入User对象。那么哪个U对象有这个功能，它将是这样的
and the address of the function. So I'm going to type in M percent type in this class double
和函数的地址。所以我要在这个双精度类中输入MPercent类型
colon and the function is called on player enter clamp state. All right. This is the
冒号，并在播放器进入钳位状态时调用该函数。好的。这是
first binding and the second binding. The delegates call on exit clamp state delegate
第一绑定和第二绑定。代表访问出口夹具状态代表
and by U object pass in this and the address. So it will be this class double colon on player
并通过U对象传递此地址和地址。所以这将是播放器上的这个类双冒号
exit clamp state. All right. That's the binding done. And the last thing to prove this is
退出夹具状态。好的。这就是装订工作。而证明这一点的最后一件事是
working and we're going to print to debug messages. So instead of this function, I'm
正在工作，我们将打印调试消息。所以我不是这个函数，而是
going to use debug print and the message is going to be entered clamp state. And inside
将使用调试打印，消息将进入钳位状态。在里面
of this function, I'm going to print the message, as it is clamp state. And that's pretty much
在此函数中，我将打印消息，因为它处于夹具状态。而这几乎就是
it. I'm going to compile. All right. I have a successful compile. I'm going to launch
它。我要去汇编一下。好的。我有一个成功的汇编。我要发射
my editor back. Go back to my editor. I'm going to test this. So click play, then press
我的编辑回来了。回到我的编辑那里。我要测试一下这个。点击播放，然后按
F and you can see I have a message printed to the screen. If I press F again, so it says
你可以看到我在屏幕上打印了一条消息。如果我再按一次F，它就会显示
as a tape clamp state, press F again entered clamp state. Great. Our delegate is working.
作为夹带状态，再次按F进入夹带状态。太棒了。我们的代表正在工作。
I'm going to try to climb to the top and it says exit a clamp state. Great. Everything
我要试着爬到顶端，它说退出夹持状态。太棒了。一切
is working as expected. And for our vaulting, the entering and exiting happened almost at
正在发挥预期的作用。而对于我们的跳马来说，进场和退场几乎发生在8点。
the same frame. All right. This is working as expected. So this is the roadmap that we
同样的画面。好的。这起到了预期的作用。这就是我们的路线图
will follow to create our hopping. And in order for our player to add and remove input
会紧随其后来创造我们的跳跃。为了让我们的玩家添加和删除输入
mapping context, our custom moving component needs to notify our character when we have
映射上下文时，我们的自定义移动组件需要通知角色
entered the clamp state and using delegate can help us to do the job. So feel free to
进入夹具状态，使用Delegate可以帮助我们完成工作。所以你可以随意地
refer back to the video if you need help and I'll see you in the next lecture.
如果你需要帮助，请参考视频，我将在下一节课上见到你。
[Music]
[音乐]